（綱手つなで）久しぶりだな ２人とも
It's been a long time, you two.
修業の成果はあったんだろうな
I'm sure your training produced
good results, right?
（自来也じらいや）なんの成果もなしに
戻ってきたとでも思っとるのか？
Do you think we came back
without making progress?
（うずまきナルト）
バッチリだってばよ
It went perfectly!
Then show me
those results immediately.
（綱手）では 早速
成果を見せてもらおう
（ナルト）見せるって…
Show you...?
（綱手）ある男の相手をしてもらう
You will take on a particular man.
I didn't send him on any missions
for the past several days
このために わざわざ
ここ数日は任務にもつけず
待機してもらっていたのだ
and had him stand by
for this very purpose.
その相手とは…
Your opponent will be...
Come in!
（綱手）入れ！
あ…
Hello.
（奈良ならシカマル）どうも～
（春野はるのサクラ）
シカマル テマリさん
Shikamaru! Temari!
Look who's here!
ほら 誰だと思う？
（シカマル）あっ
（テマリ）んっ
Naruto.
（シカマル）ナルト
Hey! That is you isn't it, Naruto!
おい ナルトじゃねえか
（ナルト）あっ シカマル
Shikamaru!
（テマリ）こいつ あのちびか
This is...that little shrimp...?
（シカマル）お前 帰ってきてたのか
So you're back?
ああ けさ帰ってきた
Yeah, I got back this morning.
（シカマル）ヘヘッ
なんかバカさ加減が抜けたっつうか
You don't look
as stupid as before...
なんつうか…
変わったか？ おい
I mean, hey, have you changed?
ん ヌヒヒヒ…
いや 変わってない
No, he hasn't.
（シカマル）ハハ… やっぱり
Oh...I thought so.
（ナルト）サクラちゃん
Sakura.
（綱手）ハハハ…
（シズネ）フフフ
ん？ じゃあ 俺の相手は
シカマルってわけか？
Then, does this mean
you're my opponent, Shikamaru?
Opponent? What do you mean?
相手？ なんのことだ
俺は書類を届けに来ただけだぞ
I just came to deliver
some documents.
Huh? You're not
my opponent, Shikamaru?
（ナルト）ん？
シカマルじゃないのか
じゃあ…
Then...?
誰だっけ？
Who're you again?
覚えてないのか？
You don't remember me?
（綱手）ナルト
お前の相手はそっちじゃない
Naruto, that's not your opponent.
（綱手）あっちだ
（ナルト）ん？
He's out there.
おっ
（はたけカカシ）
でかくなったな ナルト
You sure got tall...Naruto.
（カカシ）よっ！
Yo!
あ…
カカシ先生
Kakashi Sensei!
♪～
～♪
The Akatsuki Makes Its Move
（ナルト）先生ってば
全然 変わってねえってばよ
Sensei, you haven't changed one bit!
あっ そうだ
Oh yeah.
Listen, listen...
I've got a present for you, Sensei.
あのさ あのさ
カカシ先生にプレゼントが
あるんだってばよ
（カカシ）ん？
This is sure a nostalgic sight.
懐かしい光景だな
はい
Yes, it is...
（カカシ）なに～！
What?!
You got me... Th-This is...
お前 こ こ… これは…
（ナルト）これってば
This is the first new title in
the Make-Out series in three years!
イチャイチャシリーズ
３年ぶりの最新作
すんげえ つまんないけど
先生 好きなんだろ？
I think it's totally boring,
but you like this stuff,
don't you, Sensei?!
（自来也）ふん アホが
That idiot...No way could
a kid understand the appeal.
あのおもしろさが
ガキに分かってたまるかっての
おまけに まだ世間に出てない
レアものだってのに
And on top of that,
it's a very rare item that hasn't
even been released yet...
（カカシ）うおお…
よし！ お楽しみは
その辺で終わりだ カカシ
All right! That's enough fun
for now, Kakashi.
（ナルト）ん？
まさか 俺の相手って
Don't tell me...
Are you  my opponent...?
（カカシ）う～ん
ちょっと違うかな
Hmm, not quite...
いやあ サクラと会うのも
久しぶりだねえ
Gee, it's been a while
since I saw you too, Sakura.
（サクラ）はい カカシ先生
Yes, it has, Kakashi Sensei.
My opponent will be...
（カカシ）俺が相手するのは…
ナルト サクラ
Naruto...and Sakura,
the both of you!
お前ら２人だ
（サクラ）えっ
（ナルト）なっ…
カカシ先生が相手？
Kakashi Sensei's our opponent...
（綱手）カカシ相手にどれだけやれるか
I want to see what you
can do against Kakashi...
I will determine your status
in the future based on the results.
その結果いかんによって
今後の お前たちの処遇を決める
ん… 処遇ねえ
Status, eh?
サクラ お前とて
Sakura, show me that
ムダに 私の元で
過ごしたわけでもあるまい
you weren't just wasting
your time training under me.
Yes, ma'am!
はい
（カカシ）それじゃあ すぐに始めるか
Then, shall we get right to it?
（サクラ）ん…
（ナルト）あ…
（カカシ）…と言いたいところだけど
That's what I'd like  to say.
ナルトも帰ってきたばっかで
疲れているだろう
But since you just got back Naruto,
you must be tired.
少し休憩をやる
I'll give you a short rest.
I'm not particularly tired
or anything!
俺は 別に
疲れちゃいねえってばよ
（カカシ）あとで
第三演習場で落ち合おう
Let's meet up at
the Third Training Grounds later.
じゃあな
See ya.
Why's he in such a hurry?
（シズネ）どうしたんでしょう
あんなに急いで
だいたいの見当はつくがな
I have a pretty good idea...
本を読む気だな
He's going to read his book.
Oh!
ああ～
With that look he had,
there's no doubt about it.
あの顔は 間違いなくそうね
（自来也）発売前のわしの本を
手に入れたんじゃ
That's the obvious reaction
after getting an unreleased copy
of one of my books.
当然の反応だのォ
（ナルト）カカシ先生ってば
俺たちの修業の成果より
That Kakashi Sensei.
Is that stupid book
more important to him
あんなくだらない本のほうが
大切なのかよ
than the results of our training?
（サクラ）まあ そのおかげで
Well, now we can discuss our strategy
against Kakashi Sensei.
こっちは カカシ先生相手の戦略を
打ち合わせできるんだけど
んで…
So, are you guys on a date?
そちらはデートですかい？
んん… そんなんじゃねえよ
It's not like that.
ふんっ 冗談はよせ
なんで こんなヤツと
Heh! Cut out the jokes.
Why would I be on
a date with this guy?
もうすぐ中忍ちゅうにん試験がある
It's almost time for
the Chunin Exams.
その打ち合わせで 砂と木ノ葉このはを
行ったり来たりしてるだけだ
I've just been going back and forth
between the Sand and the Leaf
for meetings concerning the Exams.
んで めんどくせーが
俺 試験の係になってっから
And although it's a pain,
I've been put in charge
of the Exams...
砂の使者さんを案内するよう
言われてるだけだ
I've just been told to act as
a guide for the Sand messenger.
中忍試験か
Chunin Exams, huh...?
That sure takes me back...
懐かしいな
（シカマル）あっ
Oh...
んで お前 どうすんだ？ ナルト
So what're you going to do, Naruto?
（ナルト）あ？ 何が？
About what?
（シカマル）んっ 何がって…
中忍試験だよ
About the Chunin Exams.
俺らと同期で中忍になってないの
お前だけだぜ
You're the only one from our class
who hasn't become a Chunin.
びえ～
What?!
じゃ… じゃあ
サクラちゃんも中忍？
Th-Then, you're also a Chunin, Sakura?
（サクラ）フフ～ン そうよ
Heh-heh...That's right.
ついでといっちゃ なんだが
砂隠れのカンクロウとこの人
And just for the record,
Kankuro, this person here,
and Neji who's one grade above us
are already Jonin.
あ～ それから１級上のネジは
もう上忍だ
（ナルト）かあ…
Huh?!
あっ
じゃあ 我愛羅があら　我愛羅は？
Then what about Gaara?!
（バキ）風影かぜかげ様 そろそろ会議です
Lord Kazekage...
The meeting is about to begin.
Okay.
（我愛羅）分かった
（ナルト）そうか
I see...
So Gaara became the Kazekage, huh...?
我愛羅は風影になったのか
すげえ
That's awesome...
（シカマル）あ？
俺も負けてらんねえってばよ
I won't be outdone!
ぜってえ火影ほかげになってやる
I'll become the Hokage,
no matter what!
見てろよ 我愛羅
Just you wait, Gaara!
（サクラ）やっぱり
少しは成長したみたい
I guess...
he has matured a little, after all.
（自来也）どうだ
おもしろいだろうのォ
What do you think?!
Pretty good, huh...?
わしの最高傑作だからのォ フフ…
It is my finest work.
I leave Naruto in your care
as promised...
約束どおり
ナルトはお前に預けるからの
（カカシ）あいつ 少しは
成長してればありがたいんですがねえ
It'd be nice if he's grown
at least a little.
ふんっ
抜かりがあると思うか？
Heh... You'd think I've slipped up?
気を抜くと お前も出し抜かれるぞ
You'll get beaten out
if you get careless.
（カカシ）そりゃ 頼もしい
Well, that's encouraging to hear.
ヤツらの動きが活発になってきた
And their actions are
gaining momentum.
（バキ）
この数年で わが里の力は安定し
Over the past several years,
the strength of our village
has stabilized,
各同盟国の隠れ里との交流も
豊かなものになりました
and relations with the Hidden Villages
in each allied land have prospered.
（バキ）特に 新人育成には
In particular,
we have achieved good results
in our development of recruits
with the curriculum incorporating...
木こノ葉は隠がくれの演習プログラムを
取り入れたカリキュラムで
高い成果が出ています
the training program
from the Leaf Village.
The Chunin Exams are almost here.
I look forward to the results.
（砂忍の上役）
もうすぐ中忍試験だな
そりゃあ 結果が楽しみだわい
（由良ゆうら）ただ
However... at this time,
with the Chunin Exams upon us,
また中忍試験のこの時期に
よからぬうわさが
there is a nasty rumor
going around...
なんだ由良
What is it, Yura?
暁あかつきという組織の名を
聞いたことがありますか？
Have you heard of the organization
called the "Akatsuki"?
I see... So they're finally
making their move.
（カカシ）そうですか
ヤツらがついに
（自来也）ある程度
予想されていたことではあるがのォ
It's something we were expecting
to a degree, though.
うん
The Akatsuki, huh...?
（カカシ）暁か
The Akatsuki is a mysterious organization
composed of a dozen or so Shinobi.
（由良）暁というのは
十数名ほどの
忍びによって構成されている...
謎の組織です
The members of the organization
are vicious S-Rank criminals
メンバーはいずれも
ビンゴブックに載ってる
凶悪なＳ級犯罪者ばかりです
all listed in the Bingo Book.
Of those identified...
面の割れているものの中には
there is Itachi Uchiha from
the Village Hidden in the Leaves
木ノ葉隠れ里出身で
一夜にして みずからの一族を
滅亡に追い込んだ
who drove his own clan
to annihilation in one night.
うちはイタチ
There is Kisame Hoshigaki
かつては 忍刀しのびがたな七人衆の１人で
霧隠きりがくれの怪人と呼ばれた
who was once a member of
the Seven Ninja Swords Men of the Mist.
He was known as
the phantom of the Mist.
干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ
And there is Orochimaru
以前 木ノ葉崩しを画策し
先代の風影様を暗殺した大蛇丸おろちまるも
who once plotted the destruction
of the Leaf...
and assassinated
the previous Kazekage.
It is said he used to be
a member of this organization.
かつては この組織の
メンバーだったといわれています
Why have they started taking
such dramatic action?
（カカシ）ヤツらが派手な動きを
見せ始めている理由は なんです？
What's their goal?
目的は？
そこまでは わしにも分からん
That's beyond me at this point...
What I do  know...
分かっとるのは…
is that they're after
what's inside Naruto.
ナルトの中のものを
狙っとるということ
And...that they've got something evil
in mind.
そして
何か よからぬことを
考えとるということじゃ
I passed on this information
各国の警備担当者には
情報を流しておいた
to those in charge of security
for each land.
すぐに 警戒態勢を
敷いてくれるとよいのだがのォ
I sure hope they tighten up
their security immediately.
うん
そうか
I see... I'd heard the rumors...
うわさだけは
耳にしたことがあるが
So the organization in question
is finally taking action...
例の組織が ついに…
情報源が あの伝説の三忍さんにんの１人
自来也様でしたので
The source of the information
is Lord Jiraiya,
one of the legendary Sannin.
勝手とは思いましたが
So prior to the meeting,
I took the liberty of issuing an order
to increase Village security.
会議に先んじて
里を固める命を出しておきました
Anbu Black Ops masters
have already been stationed
里周辺の要所には すでに
暗部あんぶの手練てだれも配置してあります
at key points around the village.
いかに力のある忍といえど
No matter how powerful
the Shinobi may be,
力ずくで侵入することは
できないでしょう
they will not be able
to infiltrate by force.
暁のメンバーは
I hear the members of the Akatsuki
wear black clothing
黒い衣に赤い雲模様のマントを
着用していると聞きます
in addition to capes with
a red cloud pattern on them.
そのようなものが現れたときは
I ordered security to attack
with full force
全力でたたくように
命じておきました
should they see someone
fitting that description.
Now then...
the meeting is adjourned.
（バキ）では これで
会議は終わりにする
さすがだな 由良よ
いち早く動いていたとは
Well done, Yura.
I never thought you'd take action
so quickly.
（由良）フフッ
I have also served as
a superior for four years.
私も 上役を４年も
務めさせていただている身です
里のためには…
It is my intention...
to always make decisions
while considering...
どうするのが…
いちばんよいか…
（上役）ん？
（由良）常に… 考えて…
what's in the best interest...
of the...village.
判断している…
つもり… です…
SEAL
あっ あ…
う…
What's the matter?
（上役）どうした？
（由良）いえ なんでもありません
Nothing... It's nothing at all...
少し寝不足で
I just haven't slept much...
そうか
体には気をつけろよ
I see...You need to take care
of yourself.
（由良）ありがとうございます
Thank you for your concern.
んん…
I see... That's right...
（由良）そうか そうだったな
（デイダラ）そうか
I see. So we have to deal
with this one,
大蛇丸のところにやったヤツより
こっちが先か
then go after the guy
we sent to Orochimaru, huh?
It seems he turned traitor
and leaked information about us.
どうやら オイラたちの情報を
垂れ流しにするような
裏切り者になってるらしいが うん
（サソリ）しかたねえだろうが
It can't be helped.
Even I don't know what happens
after the Jutsu is cast.
術をかけたあとどうなるかなんて
俺は知らん
それより その袋だけで
大丈夫なのか？
More importantly,
will just that bag be enough?
Our opponent will be
using the Jinchuriki.
相手は人柱力じんちゅうりきを使うんだぜ
All of my Jutsu are works of art.
（デイダラ）オイラの術は
すべて芸術だ
それに ちゃ～んと
オハコも持ってきている うん
And I made sure to
bring my specialty.
After all, our opponent
is the One-Tailed.
なんせ相手は一尾だからな うん
Third Training Grounds
ああ～ もう
カカシ先生ってば
いつまで待たせる気だよ
Is Kakashi Sensei
going to make us wait forever?!
まっ 昔っからだけどね
Well, he's always been like this.
（ナルト）は～ 全く…
Geez, it'd be nice if he'd show
a little improvement.
ちょっとは進歩してほしいってばよ
フフッ
（ナルト）あ…
Oh, sorry about that.
（カカシ）やあ わりい わりい
As it happens, I ran into an old woman
in trouble on my way here and...
実は ここに来る途中で
おばあさんが困ってて…
（ナルト･サクラ）はい それウソ！
- Okay! That's a lie!
This place...
kind of takes me back.
なんか懐かしいってばよ ここ
うん
（カカシ）本日の課題
Your task for today is
それは この鈴を
俺から昼までに奪い取ることだ
to take these bells away from me
by this afternoon.
Those unable to get a bell
will get no lunch.
奪えなかったものは昼飯抜き！
（ナルト）えっ！
What?!
（カカシ）あれに縛りつけた上
目の前で 俺が弁当食うから
You'll be tied to those posts and
then I'll eat your lunch right
in front of you.
Oh, come to think of it,
（カカシ）あ～ そういや
ここは お前たちの
最初の演習場所だったっけなあ
this was your first Training Ground,
wasn't it?
第七班
Squad Seven...
The Three-Man Squad, huh...?
スリーマンセルか
（カカシ）あのときは
サスケもいたっけな
We had Sasuke with us...
back then, didn't we?
Don't go!
（サクラ）行かないで！
If you do, I'll scream...!
行くなら 私 大声出して…
Sakura.
（サスケ）サクラ
Thanks.
ありがとう
（サクラ）あ…
サスケ君…
Sasuke.
Sasuke!
サスケ！
Yo, goofball.
（サスケ）よう
ウスラトンカチ
（カカシ）ん？
（ナルト）俺ってば なんであのとき…
（カカシ）サスケの名前は
こいつらには禁句だな
Sasuke's name is
off limits for these guys...
（鈴の音）
（ナルト）あっ
（カカシ）まっ
どれだけ成長したのか見てやる
Well... Let's see how much
you've grown.
サスケのことは
諦めちゃいないんだろ？
You haven't given up
on Sasuke, have you?
（サクラ）もちろん
Absolutely not!
そのために 修業を
積んできたんだってばよ
That's why I continued my training!
（カカシ）うん
The rules are the same
as when we first met.
ルールは 初めてお前たちと
会ったときと同じ
I don't care how you do it.
Just take a bell away from me.
どんな手を使ってもいいから
俺から鈴を取ればいい
- If you don't...
- "come at me with the intent to kill,"
（カカシ）俺を…
（ナルト）殺すつもりでこないと
"we won't
取れないから… でしょ？
（カカシ）手裏剣しゅりけん使ってもいいぞ～
俺を殺す気でこないと
取れないからな
（カカシ）フッ そのとおり
俺を殺すつもりでこないと
取れないからな
期限は あしたの日の出まで
さて 始めますか
今度は その本
読みながらやらないの？
カカシ先生
それとも もう
読み終わっちゃったんですか？
（カカシ）いや 楽しみは
あとに取っとこうと思ってね
それに まあ
今回は なんとなく…
俺も少し…
本気を出さないといけない
雰囲気だしな
（鈴の音）
（警邏けいら忍者）ん？
（警邏忍者）なんだ？
う…
黒い衣に赤い雲模様
まさか
あれは…
由良隊長に 至急 連絡を
（警邏忍者）あっ
由良隊長 例の組織のヤツらが
現れました
（由良）分かっている
心配するな すぐ終わる
（サソリ）ご苦労 由良
俺のこと思い出してくれた？
（由良）はっ サソリ様
いくぞ～！
♪～
～♪
この わしの新作が
ついにベールを脱ぐときがきた
あの名作 イチャイチャ
バイオレンスから はや３年
これぞ 時間を忘れ 呼吸を忘れ
我をも忘れる魂の最高傑作
「イチャイチャタクティクス」
木ノ葉集英堂しゅうえいどうにて
絶賛 予約受付中
みんな 買えのォ
ここで宣伝すんな こら～！
次回「修業の成果」
（うみのイルカ）よ～し
全員 そろったようだな
きょうの授業は
中忍選抜試験について復習していくぞ
いいな
火の国と同盟を
結ぶ各国の隠れ里では
年に２回 合同で
優秀な下忍を集め
中忍選抜試験を開催している
下忍から中忍へ
昇格させる
だけでなく
各国を
統治する大名に
その国の軍事力を
アピールする
場でもある
まあ つまり
己の国の名誉と威信を賭けた
戦いだといっても
過言ではないわけだ
それでは ここで問題だ
ナルトたちが
参加した試験で
みごと
中忍に昇格した
木ノ葉の忍は誰か
分かるかな？
正解は…
奈良ならシカマルだ
めんどくせーが
口癖のあいつも
今は中忍
っていうと
あいつ 俺と同じ階級か？